Guide to the Margaret Flory Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Collected Materials, Series XIII
  - Topical Files
    - General, Alphabetical
      - Missionary Strategy: " A New Era in the World-Mission of the Church," Rajah B. Manikam, 1957 (Box 96, Folder 1080)
      - Missionary Strategy: "New Forms of Mission," J. C. Smith, 1958 (Box 96, Folder 1081)
      - Missionary Strategy: "Next Steps in Mission Board-Younger Church Relations," D.T. Niles, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 1081a)
      - Missionary Strategy: "New Patterns of Obedience in Mission," M. Flory, 1960 (Box 96, Folder 1081b)
      - Missionary Strategy: "Toward a Reformulation of Objectives," M. Richard Shaull, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1082)
      - Missionary Strategy: "The Welfare Mentality (or 'Rice Christians')", 1973 (Box 96, Folder 1083)
      - Native Americans, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1084)
      - Peace, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1084a)
      - Police Brutality, 1967-1968 (Box 96, Folder 1085)
      - Politics and Theology: Political Thought of Reinhold Niebuhr, Consultation Papers, 1973 (Box 96, Folder 1085a)
      - Politics and Theology: C. Brigagao, "Groping Forward: An Essay on J. Nyerere's Political Mode of Thought", 1974 (Box 96, Folder 1085b)
      - Politics and Theology: Alan A. Aichinger, "Religion and the Maintenance of Republican Institutions: De Tocqueville On the Case of the United States" (Box 96, Folder 1085c)
      - Poverty (UPCUSA, NCCCUSA), 1964-1968 (Box 97, Folder 1086-1087)
      - Protestantism, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1088)
      - Public Relations, 1991 (Box 97, Folder 1088a)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: General, 1950-1964 (Box 97, Folder 1089-1090)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: General (NSCF), 1960-1964 (Box 97, Folder 1091)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: General, 1965-1985 (Box 97, Folder 1092-1093)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: "Black Consciousness and Higher Education" paper, Church Society for College Work, 1968 (Box 97, Folder 1094)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: Black Power, 1966-1968 (Box 97, Folder 1095)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: The Churches and Racial Discrimination (NCCCUSA), 1963 (Box 97, Folder 1096)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights:"Colorful Minorities and the White Majority" (UMHE), 1977 (Box 97, Folder 1097)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: Commission on Race and Religion (NCCCUSA), 1963-1967 (Box 98, Folder 1098)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: Ecumenical Programme to Combat Racism (WCC), 1969 (Box 98, Folder 1098a)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: International Brotherhood, 1940-1949 (Box 98, Folder 1099)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: Ministry to Blacks in Higher Education, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 1100)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: Black Manifesto (National Black Economic Development Conference), 1969 (Box 98, Folder 1101)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: National Black Economic Development Conference Sit-in at Interchurch Center, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 1102)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: National Women's Committee for Civil Rights (M. Flory, appointee), 1963 (Box 98, Folder 1103)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: Segregation, 1951-1961 (Box 98, Folder 1104)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: Sit-ins, 1960-1961 (Box 98, Folder 1105)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: Student Protest Movement Special Report, 1960 (Box 98, Folder 1106)
      - Race Relations/Civil Rights: Wilmington, Delaware, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 1107)
      - Refugees, 1979 (Box 98, Folder 1108)
      - Revolution: Speeches by C. Oglesby, 1965-1966 (Box 98, Folder 1109)
      - Student Mood, 1965-1969 (Box 98, Folder 1110)
      - Student Protests, 1965-1969 (Box 98, Folder 1111)
      - Study Abroad, 1958, 1960 (Box 98, Folder 1112)
      - Teaching Opportunities Abroad, 1964, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 1113)
      - Technology, 1964, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 1114)
      - Transcultural Allegories (Melvin Yosso), 1977 (Box 99, Folder 1115)
      - Travel -- Collected Materials, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1116)
      - Travel -- Europe, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1117)
      - Travel -- Tours/Seminars, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1118)
      - Travel -- Certificates and Forms (Passports, Visas, Health) (Box 99, Folder 1119)
      - University Ministry: Collected Articles (UCCF Publications Office), 1957-1965 (Box 99, Folder 1120)
      - University Ministry: Collected Articles, 1957-1991, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1121-1126)
      - University Ministry: Miscellaneous Brochures, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1126a)
      - University Ministry: Episcopal Church, 1963 (Box 100, Folder 1127)
      - University Ministry: Danforth Foundation Study, 1963 (Box 100, Folder 1128)
      - University Ministry: Alsid de Chambeau, "An Exploratory Ministry in Higher Education", 1967 (Box 100, Folder 1128a)
      - University Ministry: Campus Ministry Women, 1975-1977 (Box 100, Folder 1129)
      - University Ministry: International and Minority Students (Box 100, Folder 1130)
      - University Ministry: Local Ministries, 1964-1990 (Box 100, Folder 1131)
      - University Ministry: New York Council of Churches, Manual, 1982 (Box 100, Folder 1131a)
      - Urbanization, 1962-1979 (Box 100, Folder 1132-1134)
      - Urbanization: Dept. of the Urban Church (UPCUSA), 1963 (Box 100, Folder 1135)
      - Urbanization: "Population and the Asian Environment from an Asian Perspective," by Chung-Hyun Ro, 1971 (Box 100, Folder 1135a)
      - Woman as a Person, 1970-1972 (Box 100, Folder 1136)
      - Women: U.N. Decade for Women, 1980 (Box 100, Folder 1137)
      - Women: Miscellaneous, 1979, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1138)
      - Bibliographies, 1970 (Box 124, Folder 1328)
      - Drama: Articles, Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 1329)
      - Drama: Report of 1954 Religious Drama Workshops, Greenlake, WI, sponsored by NCC Division of Christian Education and American Baptist Assembly (Box 124, Folder 1330)
      - Drama: Scripts and Services (Box 124, Folder 1331)
      - Drama: Using Drama in the Church by Florence A. Moseley and J. Edward Moseley, 1939 (Box 125, Folder 1332)
      - Global Issues in Higher Education, 1981 (Box 125, Folder 1333)
      - Internationalization of Church/University, 1960-1970's (Box 125, Folder 1334)
      - Internationalization of Mission, 1967-1986 (Box 125, Folder 1335)
      - Labor Issues, 1971 (Box 125, Folder 1336)
      - Missions: Brochures and Pamphlets (Box 125, Folder 1337)
      - Missionary Strategy: Articles, Essays, Newsletters, and Reports, 1958-1981 (Box 125, Folder 1338)
      - Missionary Strategy: General, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 1339)
      - Missionary Strategy: General, 1967-1989 (Box 125, Folder 1340)
      - Missionary Strategy: "Toward a Philosophy of Student Work in the Areas of the Younger Churches," Richard Schuall, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 1341)
      - Peace, 1941 (Box 126, Folder 1342)
      - Religious Right Wing Fundamentalists, 1981 (Box 126, Folder 1343)
      - Student Movements, 1981 (Box 126, Folder 1344)
      - Student Protests, 1968 (Box 126, Folder 1345)
      - Theological Education in Third World, 1974-1981 (Box 126, Folder 1346)
      - University Ministry, booklets, 1959, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 1347)
      - Women: Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 126, Folder 1348)
      - Worship: Pamphlets, 1940-1979 (Box 126, Folder 1349)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series XIV
  - Travel
    - World Tour: Impressions of an Ecumenical Journey, 1952-1953 (Box 101, Folder 1139)
    - World Tour: Impressions of an Ecumenical Journey (copy 2), 1952-1953 (Box 101, Folder 1140)
    - World Tour: Japan, 1952-1953 (Box 101, Folder 1141)
    - World Tour: The Philippines, 1952-1953 (Box 101, Folder 1142)
    - World Tour: Thailand, 1952-1953 (Box 101, Folder 1143)
    - World Tour: India, 1952-1953 (Box 101, Folder 1144-1145)
    - World Tour: Pakistan, 1952-1953 (Box 101, Folder 1146)
    - World Tour: Near East, 1952-1953 (Box 101, Folder 1147)
    - World Tour: Europe, 1952-1953 (Box 101, Folder 1148)
    - Asia Tour, 1961-1962 (Box 101, Folder 1149)
    - Asia Tour, 1967 (Box 101, Folder 1150)
    - China - Diary Reflections, 1976 (Box 101, Folder 1150a)
    - Memorabilia from Summer Session at Union Theological Seminary, 1940 (Box 126, Folder 1350)
    - Correspondence from M. Flory in Japan, 1948 (Box 126, Folder 1351)
    - Correspondence, News Clippings, and Programs re: M. Flory 1948 in Asia, 1949 (Box 126, Folder 1352)
    - World Tour: Schedule, 1952-1953 (Box 126, Folder 1353)
    - China: "Day by Day in the People's Republic of China" by M. Flory, 1976 (Box 126, Folder 1354)
    - Cuba, 1995 (Box 126, Folder 1355)
    - Autograph book from students at Joshi Dai, Japan, 1948 (Box 126, Folder 1356)
  - Biographical information
    - General Information, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1150b)
    - Resumés and Biographical Sketches, 1972-1981 (Box 101, Folder 1151)
    - Life Insurance Policy, 1974 (Box 101, Folder 1152)
    - Morningside Gardens Apartment Information, 1975, 1991 (Box 101, Folder 1153)
    - Retirement Event, 1980 (Box 101, Folder 1154)
    - Correspondence re: Flavio Ceccon (French), 1980 (Box 101, Folder 1155)
    - "Initiating and Sustaining Ecumenical Ministries: A Study of the Ministry of Margaret Flory, 1951-1980" - A Dissertation/Project for the Doctor of Ministry by Barbara Anne Roche. San Francisco Theological Seminary, 1983 (Box 110, Folder 1242)
    - Flory Conference Hall, John Knox Centre, Geneva, 1994 (Box 101, Folder 1156)
    - Personal Donation to Cuban Medical Project, 2000 (Box 101, Folder 1157)
    - Christmas Memorabilia: Services, leaflets, cards, miscellaneous (Box 113, Folder 1292)
    - Christmas Memorabilia: Stories (Box 113, Folder 1292g)
    - 90th birthday Event, 2004 (Box 101, Folder 1158)
    - Wauseon, Ohio/Ohio University years: Correspondence, programs, etc, 1929-1939 (Box 127, Folder 1356)
    - Ohio University Debate Team, notes, 1932-1938 (Box 127, Folder 1357)
    - Ohio University, news clippings, 1932-1939 (Box 127, Folder 1358)
    - General Correspondence (Box 127, Folder 1359)
    - Biographical Sketches and news clippings, 1946, 1980, 1991, 1996, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 1360)
    - Flory Conference Hall, John Knox Centre, Geneva, 1993 (Box 127, Folder 1361)
    - Personal Donation to Washington, D.C. Martin Luther Kind Jr., National Memorial Project Foundation, incl. photograph, 2003 (Box 127, Folder 1362)
    - Christmas Memorabilia: Christmas letters from M. Flory, 1991-1999 (Box 127, Folder 1363)
    - 90th Birthday Event, 2004 (Box 127, Folder 1364)
    - Collegewalk Retirement Community, 2004-2007 (Box 127, Folder 1365)
    - Letters of Remembrance upon M. Flory's Death, 2009 (Box 127, Folder 1366)
    - Silver engraved plate: "To Margaret from the IRO - 13th May 2004" (Box 137)
    - Paperweight from United Presbyterian Church, USA to Margaret M. Flory "In Gratitude For Your Faithful Service 1944-1980" (Box 137)
    - Citation from Tokyo Woman's Christian University to M. Flory for years of service, 1988 (Box OV1)
    - "Women of Faith Recognition" award from the Joint Committee on Women of the Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.), 1987 (Box OV1)
  - Autobiographical writings
    - Moments in Time: One Woman's Ecumenical Journey, 1995 (Box 110, Folder 1243)
    - From Past to Future: Experiments in Global Bridging - re. the ministry of Margaret Flory with the World Student Christian Federation and Office of Student World Relations of the Presbyterian Church, USA, 1997 (Box 110, Folder 1244)
    - Dear House, Mission Becomes You - Gilmor Sloane House, Stony Point Center, Stony Point, NY 1949-1999, 2000 (Box 110, Folder 1245)
    - "Land of Waterfalls Silver Arts" Flory selection in Aunt Margie Remembers, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 1246)
    - Articles written by M. Flory incl. "Drama with a Mission," and "A New Ministry in a New World", 1953, 1963, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 1367)
    - Book Proposal for Many Voices, One Melody by M. Flory and Marjorie Megivern, 2005-2006 (Box 127, Folder 1368)
    - Notes on "Flory Stories" and Many Voices, One Melody (Box 127, Folder 1369)
  - Notes and Notebooks
    - Drama in the Church, 1939, 1941 (Box 128, Folder 1370)
    - Lecture notes and essays for Christian Ethics class at Union Theological Seminary, 1940 (Box 128, Folder 1371)
    - Lecture notes for History, Literature, and Religion of the New Testament class at Union Theological Seminary, 1940 (Box 128, Folder 1372)
    - Lecture notes for Personal Counseling class at Union Theological Seminary, 1940 (Box 128, Folder 1373)
    - Lecture notes for Christian Faith and Philosophy of History class at Union Theological Seminary, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 1374)
    - "Religion in Higher Education: an Approach toward Training Students for Lay Leadership" by M. Flory incl. notes, 1941 (Box 128, Folder 1375)
    - Lecture notes on Use of the Bible class at Union Theological Seminary, 1941 (Box 128, Folder 1376)
    - Collection of ideas and quotations for speeches, 1950-1951 (Box 129, Folder 1377)
    - Collection of ideas and articles for speeches re: foreign policy, race relations, poetry, and scripture, 1952-1954 (Box 129, Folder 1378)
    - Calendars, Day Planners, n.d., 1957, 1980, 1988, 2003 (Box 129, Folder 1380)
    - Travel Logs and Information, 1972, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 1381)
    - M. Flory's planning notebook while Program Director for Gilmor-Sloane House, Stony Point, NY, 1980's (Box 129, Folder 1382)
    - CAREE, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1383)
    - Church History, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1383a)
    - Conferences, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1384)
    - Dante Alighieri's Divine Comedy, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1385)
    - FIM, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 1386-1387)
    - International Mission, Poland, Asia, Central America (Box 130, Folder 1388)
    - Lecture notes on "The Christian Religion and Problem of Justice" (Box 131, Folder 1389)
    - Lecture notes on How We Got Our Bible class, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1390)
    - John Makey's "Preface to Christian Theology", n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1391)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1392-1394)
    - Planning Church Activities, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1395)
    - Quotations, Stories, Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 1396)
    - Racial Prejudice, International Student Mission Reports, SCM, articles, 1950-1960? (Box 132, Folder 1397)
    - Resource Book re: International Affairs and Missions (Box 132, Folder 1398)
    - SCM and SVM (Box 132, Folder 1399)
    - Scripture, Written Prayers, Quotations, Sermons, etc, n.d. (Box 132, Folder 1400)
    - Theology, n.d. (Box 132, Folder 1401-1402)
    - To Do Lists, Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1403-1405)
    - Various Lectures, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1406)
    - World Development, Poverty, and International Missions (Box 133, Folder 1407)
    - Westminster Years incl. notes on Theology, Quotations, etc., 1940-1944 (Box 134, Folder 1408)
    - WSCF Life and Mission of the Church Emphasis (Box 134, Folder 1409)
    - WSCF and SCM (Box 134, Folder 1410)
- Audio-visual Materials, Series XV
  - Photographs
    - Misc. photos of MF. Additional photographs are filed elsewhere with other materials from the event or program documented., n.d. (Box 102)
    - M. Flory miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 134, Folder 1411)
    - M. Flory early days, 1920's-1940's (Box 134, Folder 1412)
    - Reverend Tamaki Uemura (oversize), 1946 (Box OV1)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Ohio University years, 1930's (Box 134)
    - Trip to Japan, 1948 (Box 135)
    - Margaret Flory and Friends, Volumes One and Two (Box 135)
    - Old Timers' Celebration, Albums 1 and 2, 2006 (Box 135)
    - College Walk Events, n.d. (Box 135)
    - 80th Birthday, 1994 (Box 136)
    - Black Mountain Birthday Party, 2004 (Box 136, Folder 1415)
    - 90th Birthday (removed from binder), 2004 (Box 136, Folder 1416-1417)
    - 92nd Birthday, 2006 (Box 137)
    - 4 Untitled Scrapbooks, n.d. (Box 137)
  - Slides
    - Slide set: "Work, Learn, Serve" - Office Student Work, UPCUSA, 1950s (Box 102)
    - Slide set - students at events - possibly Student Volunteer Movement, 1950s (Box 102)
    - PowerPoint slides, M. Flory retrospective, n.d. (Box 134, Folder 1413-1414)
  - Filmstrips
    - Set of five filmstrips with booklets containing commentary by Pearl Buck: "Through China's Gateway: I. "In the Chinese Manner"; II. "China's Children"; III. "Food for China"; IV. "A Nation of Scholars"; V. "China's Tomorrow", 1946 (Box 102)
    - Filmstrips: "Glories of the Past in China" (S.V.E.); "Youth and Church" (World Council of Religion Education; " We Build with Thee" (Central Youth Committee, National Christian Council of India) (Box 102)
    - Filmstrip and audiocassette sets: "China: Take Three" (Friendship Press); "Once Upon a Horse" (Friendship Press) (Box 102)
  - Audio tapes
    - 1 tape (reel to reel) Frontier Intern Reports: September Commission meeting, North Park, Chicago, September 9, 1963, 1964 (Box 102)
    - 21 tapes (reel to reel) from 1965 Frontier Internship in Mission Orientation session, Princeton, NJ (Box 102)
  - Vinyl LP Records
    - Festival of Nations of the 18th Ecumenical Conference on World Ministries, Athens, Ohio, 1960 (Box OV1)
    - For These We Pray, Margaret Flory, Philippe Maury, Robert Orr, and others: The Universal Day of Prayer for Students (Box OV1)